<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Koji Andria</title>
    <link>https://ko-sinus.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Koji Andria</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ko-sinus.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pediatric Robotic Arm</title>
      <link>https://ko-sinus.github.io/projects/2021-07-24-assistive-robotic-arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ko-sinus.github.io/projects/2021-07-24-assistive-robotic-arm/</guid>
      <description>This was the first human-computer interaction for healthcare project I made. It was intended for an 11 years old French child named Emilie.
Before I go into the beautiful details behind it all, here is a video promoting our success :
At the time, I was working at the HumanLab Saint-Pierre (actually, if on their homepage you see a child holding a weird thing with a motor attached to it, this is Emilie !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moral Uncertainty for AI</title>
      <link>https://ko-sinus.github.io/projects/2020-07-02-moraluncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ko-sinus.github.io/projects/2020-07-02-moraluncertainty/</guid>
      <description>I had the opportunity to work at TU Delft, the oldest technical university in The Netherlands, which also happens to be ranked among the top 10 engineering and technology universities in the world. It may sound cool, but the coolest was the proposed project : I was offered to work on the ethical decision making process of autonomous systems, with a focus on autonomous vehicles. I was there to work on the understanding and modeling of decision-making mechanisms incorporating normative uncertainty (uncertainty on which ethical theory is the most appropriate) for autonomous systems, and how to take human values and credences towards ethical principles (both at an individual and society&amp;rsquo;s scales) into account when making critical decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TEDxIMTMinesAles</title>
      <link>https://ko-sinus.github.io/projects/2020-01-16-tedximtminesales/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ko-sinus.github.io/projects/2020-01-16-tedximtminesales/</guid>
      <description>This is one of my biggest non-technological initiative. During my 1st year as a graduate student, I gathered a few of my classmates, some of my university&amp;rsquo;s administrators, some CEOs and regional actors and a few brillant minds and I reunited them for a TEDx conference.
Below are the official recordings from TEDxTalks YouTube channel. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of topics covered in there : biomimicry, emotional AI, climate change or even prosthetics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
